# Victor Klynets

# Full-stack JS Developer

Kyiv | +380509721609 | vityok3458@gmail.com

in ua.linkedin.com/in/victor-klynets

#### About me

I am a Full-stack JS Developer with a decent experience in architecting and building web applications and finding new, more flexible, highly efficient, more synthetic as well as more performing and elegant ways to do it.

A far-sighted problem preventer. Being highly adaptable, I'm able to quickly pick up and work with any architecture or libraries required. I can estimate the time needed to complete a task (and a project), plan and lead the work of a team of 5-7 people to complete a project respecting the deadlines.

Passionate about creating a favorable work environment through effective coordination and communication with managers, designers, developers and clients to produce stand-out work. Good analytical thinking with talent for identifying, scrutinizing and improving work processes

# **Employment**

# Full-stack JS Developer

January 2017 - February 2019

## Coingaming

- Building an interconnected architecture of applications
- Configuring CircleCI and GitlabCI
- Managing and deploying with *Kubernetes*
- Creating a microservice architecture using NodeJS combined with GraphQL
- Creating isomorphic applications using Meteor
- Developing Progressive Web Applications with React and Relay
- Creating bot applications using NodeJS
- Mentoring and tutoring new team members

# Front-end developer

February 2016 - October 2016

#### Mixera

As a Lead Front-end Developer my responsibilities were:

- Making Single Page Applications with ExtJS and React/Redux
- Creating custom solutions and working with a large project
- Analyzing performance and developing better solutions
- Working in a team and managing tasks

# Freelance Web Developer

November 2015 - January 2016

# Independant Freelancer

- Developed websites for different clients
- Identified issues with existing web-sites and introduced smart and efficient fixes
- Conducted correspondence with clients to obtain more information and discussed design options as well as suggested relevant and unique product solutions
- Determined appropriate architecture to achieve the best troubleshooting options

# **Projects**

Student course "Introduction to Frontend

September 2016 - November 2016

Development"

Co-founder and speaker of the course

## Education

Bachelor's Degree NTUU Kyiv Polytechnic Institute Studying software engineering.

2014 - 2018

## Soft Skills

- English(upper-intermediate), Hungarian(native speaker), Ukrainian(native speaker), Russian(native speaker)
- Problem solver with a can do attitude
- Good understanding of industrial and organization psychology principles
- High level of communication
- Highly self- motivated and directed
- Good analytical thinking with talent for identifying, scrutinizing and improving work processes
- Equally comfortable working as a member of a team and independently

## **Hard Skills**

Performance optimization

Web page first loading time and Speed Index

Frontend Development

Building Single Page Applications and Progressive Web Applications with Server Side Rendering.

**Backend Development** 

Architect, implement and maintain scalable backend software. (Redis, RabbitMQ, Docker)

JavaScript

Great knowledge of JavaScript (ES5-ES8).

JavaScript Frameworks and Libraries

Meteor, Sequelize, Mongoose, Express, React, Relay, Redux, Vue.is, ¡Query, D3.is, ExtJS, Jest, Jasmine, Angular, moment, i18next, socket.io, cron, lodash,

winston and lots of other

Databases

- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- MySQL

Build systems and module bundlers

Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, Bower